A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller papers FA002
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, C; 34.4 cubic ft. 86 boxes
  - Office, O; 20.0 cubic ft. 50 boxes
    - Sheridan - Shute, 121.0 pages (Reel 35, Frame 0428, Box 41, Folder 308)
      Baptist Church; sheriff's jury; fund for widow and children of General Philip H. Sheridan; paper-holder invention; job applicant; Society of Friends of Foreigners in Distress; William T. Sherman Statue; Cleveland Baptist Union; personal aid; Congregational Church; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); real estate; Prohibition General Committee; old oil man; gold and silver mines in California and Nevada; Judson Memorial Church; horses; Oberlin College; American Humane Education Society; distribution of "Black Beauty," by Anna Sewell; India missionary.
    - Sie - Simmons, J. Edward, 68.0 pages (Reel 35, Frame 0549, Box 41, Folder 309)
      Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); florist; landscape architect; Baptist Church; Colored Baptist Church; job applicant; business advice; China missionary; personal loan; Baptist Workers' Convention; Cleveland Chamber of Commerce.
    - Simmons, James B., 1881-February 1886; 135.0 pages (Reel 35, Frame 0617, Box 41, Folder 310)
      Pastor, Trinity Baptist Church; John D. Rockefeller contributions; mission work in East Side tenements; Chinese mission; Columbian University; Dwight L. Moody's School; American Baptist Publication Society; publication and distribution proposals; American Tract Society; University of Chicago; revised version of the Bible; Freedmen's schools; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s reception of Chinese into Fifth Avenue Baptist Church.
    - Simmons, James B., March 1886-1888; 109.0 pages (Reel 35, Frame 0752, Box 41, Folder 311)
    - Simmons, James B., 1889-1894; 68.0 pages (Reel 35, Frame 0861, Box 41, Folder 312)
    - Simmons, Theodore - Simpson, 29.0 pages (Reel 35, Frame 0929, Box 41, Folder 313)
      Real estate; Solar Refining Company; business loan; Kentucky Normal and Theological Institute; Congregational Church; book; job applicant; personal aid; hospital.
    - Sinclair, H. M., 1879-1881; 117.0 pages (Reel 35, Frame 0958, Box 41, Folder 314)
      Superintendent of Forest Hill estate; grounds; buildings; animals; employees.
    - Sinclair, H. M., 1882-March 1883; 106.0 pages (Page 36, Frame 0001, Box 42, Folder 315)
    - Sinclair, H. M., April 1883-1884; 121.0 pages (Reel 36, Frame 0107, Box 42, Folder 316)
    - Sinclair, H. M., 1885-April 1886; 130.0 pages (Box 42, Folder 317, Reel 36, Frame 0228)
    - Sinclair, H. M., May 1886-April 1887; 117.0 pages (Box 42, Folder 318, Reel 36, Frame 0358)
    - Sinclair, H. M., May 1887-November 1888; 122.0 pages (Box 42, Folder 319, Reel 36, Frame 0475)
    - Sinclair, H. M., December 1888-February 1890; 111.0 pages (Box 42, Folder 320, Reel 36, Frame 0597)
    - Sinclair, H. M., March 1890-February 1891; 120.0 pages (Box 43, Folder 321, Reel 36, Frame 0708)
    - Sinclair, H. M., March 1891-October 1892; 114.0 pages (Reel 36, Frame 0838, Box 43, Folder 322)
    - Sinclair, H. M., November 1892-1893; 44.0 pages (Box 43, Folder 323, Reel 36, Frame 0952)
    - Sinsabaugh - Smith, Freeman A., 173.0 pages (Box 43, Folder 324, Reel 37, Frame 0001)
      Trotting horses; nurse; St. Vincent's hospital; Orphan Asylum; Sisters of Charity; Sisters of Mercy' Lincoln Normal College (Nebraska); personal aid; interview request; Children's Home; Western New York Society for the Protection of Homeless and Dependent Children; Standard Oil Company employee; real estate; Shaw University; University of Chicago; Peddie Institute; private girls school; National League for the Protection of American Institutions; Baylor University; Baptist Church; Mexico City missionary; Yale University; Corning Free Academy; witch hazel abstract; Colby University; Mohonk Indian Conference; Mohonk Conference on the Negro Question; business loan; LaGrange Female College; drama company; Lake Erie Seminary; pearls for sale; Case School of Applied Science; Chapel Car (Northern Pacific Railroad Company lines); insurance; Chamber of Commerce Russian Relief Committee; Columbia College; Burma Baptist Seminary; pneumatic railway invention; Atoka, Indian Territory, Baptist Academy; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); Cheyenne and Arapahoe Indian Agency missionary; tax assessments; Andersonville Prison survivor; Chicago Baptist Theological Union; Sweden missionary.
    - Smith, George - Smith, William P., 100.0 pages (Box 43, Folder 325, Reel 37, Frame 0174)
      Petroleum gas invention; architect; massage expert; Williamsburg, Kentucky Institute; Baptist Church; hospital; Rutgers Female College; University of Chicago; Congregational Church; personal aid; Lake Erie Seminary; personal loan; John D. Rockefeller railroad passes; rockefeller genealogy; International Medical Missionary Society; Baptist Social Union; fuel gas invention for locomotives; Hospital Saturday and Sunday Association; England missionary.
    - Smith, William T., 1884-1890; 42.0 pages (Reel 37, Frame 0274, Box 43, Folder 326)
      Clerk of Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; benevolent committee; Josephine Mission.
    - Smith Granite Company - Speer, 118.0 pages (Reel 37, Frame 0316, Box 43, Folder 327)
      Cemetery monument; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); trotting horses; University of Chicago; comparative religion; American Baptist Home Mission Society, treasurer; John D. Rockefeller contributions; Gentlemen's Driving Association; New York Driving Club; Baptist Church; business proposal; personal aid; paintings for sale; personal loan; Solar Refining Company; Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA); Baptist Home; New York Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children; Society for Organizing Charity (report on a family); Society for the Prevention of Crime; Southwestern Baptist University; Congo missionary; excursion guide at Saranac Lake; gymnasium equipment; Madison University; job applicant; printers; Committee for the International Exposition of 1892 (World's Columbian Exhibition).
    - Spelman, B. R. - Spelman, L. P., 96.0 pages (Reel 37, Frame 0434, Box 43, Folder 328)
      Relatives; family matters; personal aid; job applicant; Mrs. John D. Rockefeller's mother; payment of bills; real estate; account with John D. Rockefeller; Standard Oil Company employee; National Temperance Society; student assistance; Olivet College.
    - Spelman, Lucy M., 1883-Octrober 1891; 135.0 pages (Box 44, Folder 329, Reel 37, Frame 0530)
      Mrs. John D. Rockefeller's adopted sister; family matters; payment of bills; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; real estate; investments; Standard Oil Trust shares; account with John D. Rockefeller; household matters.
    - Spelman, Lucy M., November 1891-1894 - Spelman, W. D., 139.0 pages (Box 44, Folder 330, Reel 37, Frame 0665)
      Mrs. John D. Rockefeller's adopted sister; family matters; payment of bills; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; real estate; investments; Standard Oil Trust shares; account with John D. Rockefeller; household matters; personal loan; job applicant; Standard Oil Company employee; Life Line Mission; F. T. Gates reports; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA).
    - Spence - Stadling, 96.0 pages (Box 44, Folder 331, Reel 37, Frame 0804)
      Baptist Church; Brooks Academy; job applicant; New Testament Institute; American Baptist Home Mission Society; attorneys; horse; personal aid; Union Steel Company; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) in Mexico; business matters; Hampton Normal and Agricultural Institute; Cooperative Workers (women); Standard Oil Trust shares; Stockwell Orphanage; University of Chicago; Protestant Deacon's Home; Cleveland Humane Society; Standard Oil Company, secretary; personal loan; refineries; sporting goods; Adirondack League Club; Horse Owners' Mutual Benefit and Indemnity Society; Sweden missionary.
    - Stafford, O. M., 75.0 pages (Box 44, Folder 332, Reel 37, Frame 0900)
      Euclid Avenue Baptist Church Sunday school; mission work; business matters; banker; insurance broker.
    - Stakely - Stearns, 170.0 pages (Box 44, Folder 333, Reel 37, Frame 0975)
      Baptist Church; Colored Baptist Church; personal aid; Standard Oil Trust (defense of trusts, history, and public relations); Christian Aid to Employment Society; personal loan; Francis Scott Key Monument Association; European travel guide; real estate; iron lands in Virginia; oxygen for inhaling; diamonds; sterling and silverware; John D. Rockefeller cousin; National League for the Protection of American Institutions; business proposal; National Temperance Society and Publication House; Constitutional Prohibitory Amendment Committee of New York; World's Temperance Congress; F. T. Gates report.
    - Stebbins - Stevens, 159.0 pages (Reel 38, Frame 0001, Box 44, Folder 334)
      Faith Home for Fallen Women; Baptist Church; personal aid; piano tuning; Standard Oil Company employee; Western Pennsylvania Classical and Scientific Institute (Baptist); Humane Society; real estate; Downtown Club of the Business Men's Republican Association; shoes; clothing; Burma missionary; business proposal; elk for sale; "The Illustrated American;" World's Columbian Exposition; Chamber of Commerce of the State of New York; Society for Providing Evangelical Religious Literature for the Blind; Stevens School; phosphate lands in Florida.
    - Stevenson - Stone, H. E., 151.0 pages (Reel 38, Frame 0160, Box 44, Folder 335)
      Shakespearean illustrations; Baptist Church; National Reform Association (National Marriage and Divorce Law); real estate; personal matters; Home of Industry and Refuge for Discharged Convicts; Chester A. Arthur Memorial; business friend of John D. Rockefeller; Cleveland Music Hall; personal aid; University and School Extension; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); timberlands in the South; Salvation Army; Standard Oil Trust shares; Standard Oil Company employee; Bureau of Justice (legal aid); Home Relief Association; Illinois Steel Company; sleigh repair; Home for Soldiers Widows and Army Nurses; stocks for sale; F. T. Gates report; painting for sale; Union Steel company; horse shoe nails; Children's Aid Society.
    - Stone, J. M. (Mrs.) - Streich, 84.0 pages (Reel 38, Frame 0311, Box 45, Folder 336)
      Antique newspaper; Baptist Church; Little Rock Baptist College (Colored); Guadalupe College for Colored Teachers and Preachers; Freedmen's Schools of the American Baptist Home Mission Society; personal aid; Wilson Mission; Industrial School; Women and Children's Dispensary; trotting horses; loan of painting for Metropolitan Museum of Art; Presbyterian Church; China missionary; University of Chicago; Faith Home for Fallen Women; German Church; Masonic Home; Germany missionary; Children's Home; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); temperance work; business loan; Women's Infirmary; Southern Baptist mission work; fossils for sale.
    - Strong, Augustus H., 1879-1887; 150.0 pages (Box 45, Folder 337, Reel 38, Frame 0395)
      Rochester Theological Seminary; personal aid; friendship; Baptist School in New York, New York; Brown University; Vassar College; revised version of the bible.
    - Strong, Augustus H., 1888-1894; 55.0 pages (Reel 38, Frame 0545, Box 45, Folder 338)
    - Strong, Bessie - Strong, Josiah, 166.0 pages (Reel 38, Frame 0600, Box 45, Folder 339)
      John D. Rockefeller's daughter; requests for funds; John D. Rockefeller's son-in-law; Walter Rauschenbusch; investment of earnings; Cornell University; personal aid; friendship; business loan; Evangelical Alliance.
    - Strong, L. B. - Sylvester, 119.0 pages (Reel 38, Frame 0766, Box 45, Folder 340)
      Personal aid; friendship; horses; India missionary; Germany missionary; University of Chicago; Thomasville Female College; Baptist Church; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); personal loan; gas service; Sunday School Festival; Browning School; South American Company; business loan; mission work; American Tract Society; University of Rochester.
    - Taber - Taylor, J. H., 168.0 pages (Box 45, Folder 341, Reel 38, Frame 0885)
      Real estate; Baptist Church; job applicant; clothing mission work; Assyrian slab; Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA); Rockford Female Seminary; Arkansas Baptist College; personal aid; yacht for sale; stock for sale; personal friend; Grant's Tomb; temperance work; freedmen's work; (Sir John) Gilbert portraits of George Washington; African Methodist Episcopal Church; Wake Forest College; Negro newspapers (defends capitalists); Inman & International Steamship Company; Italy missionary; Colored Baptist Church.
    - Taylor, J. M., 1887-1894; 158.0 pages (Reel 39, Frame 0001, Box 45, Folder 342)
      Vassar College, president; John D. Rockefeller's interest in college; John D. Rockefeller trustee; education of John D. Rockefeller's daughters; student assistance; F. T. Gates reports; Dr. Robinson's last illness.
    - Taylor, John C. - Thayer, 131.0 pages (Box 46, Folder 343, Reel 39, Frame 0159)
      Personal aid; Presbyterian Church; Baptist Church; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); Baptist education; insurance; personal loan; Deaconess Home; electric service; shoe repair; Congregational Church; Gospel Mission to the Tombs, city prison; Union League Club; summer resort; Students' Movement; F. T. Gates report; mines in Utah; business loan; Dwight L. Moody's school; Standard Oil Trust shares; job applicant; book for sale.
    - Thelberg - Thomas, Emma A., 54.0 pages (Box 46, Folder 344, Reel 39, Frame 0290)
      University of Chicago; Grande Ligne Mission, Canada; Baptist Church; Reid Institute; Episcopal Church; railroads in Chicago.
    - Thomas, Ezra A., 1880-1888; 159.0 pages (Box 46, Folder 345, Reel 39, Frame 0344)
      Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; board of trustees; life of church; Cleveland Baptist Union; German Baptist Church; search for new pastor.
    - Thomas, Ezra A., 1889-1891 - Thompson, M. T., 195.0 pages (Box 46, Folder 346, Reel 39, Frame 0503)
      Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; board of trustees; life of church; Cleveland Baptist Union; German Baptist Church; search for new pastor; real estate; Christian Church; Baptist Church; personal aid; architect; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); Republican State Convention in New York; job applicant; New York Port Society; personal loan; Brooks Military Academy; Murphy meetings; business loan; mission work; music festival; Music Hall Company of New York; book on oil; Nicaragua Canal; obituary; Standard Oil Trust executives; Otterbein University; Baptist Orphans' Home; Fifth Avenue Baptist Church.
    - Thompson, W. P. - Thrasher, 103.0 pages (Box 46, Folder 347, Reel 39, Frame 0698)
      Standard Oil Trust executives; trotting horses; social matters; John D. Rockefeller travel arrangements; Globe Oil Company; health of John D. Rockefeller; Baptist Church; Baptist Young Peoples Union of America; F. T. Gates report; Mariners' Temple; Pilgrim Temple Association; Yankton College; Gallaudet Home for Deaf Mutes; revocation of Pennsylvania Railroad Company passes; House of Good Shepherd (orphanage); German Baptist Church; India missionary; Inman & International Steamship Company; Episcopal Church; temperance publications; New York Port Society; Citizens' Law and Order League of Connecticut.
    - Thresher - Todd, A. H., 206.0 pages (Box 46, Folder 348, Reel 39, Frame 0801)
      Young Ladies Institute at Granville; Shepardson College for Women; Denison University; Ohio Baptist Woman's Education Society; France missionary; National Conservatory of Music of America; Adelbert College; Western Reserve University; personal aid; Taylor University; job applicant; West Side Frauen Verein; rubies for sale; Standard Oil Trust, assistant treasurer; Standard Oil Company employee; John D. Rockefeller western trip; student assistance; real estate; author of book; New York School of Languages; education of John D. Rockefeller's family; European travel plans; personal loans; oil market speculation; investment advice; lawsuit; job applicant; Delaware Indian missionary in Canada; Methodist Church; Cleveland Homeopathic Hospital (Huron Street); Baptist Church; American Baptist Home Mission Society; industrial development proposal in Alabama; Congregational Church.
      Researchers must use microfilm. See Reel 39, located in the Index Room, Cabinet 2, Drawer 11.; Researchers must use microfilm; see Reel 39, Frame 0801.
    - Todd, C. M. - Townsend, 145.0 pages (Reel 39, Frame 1007, Box 46, Folder 349)
      Fifth Avenue Baptist Church; Dobbs Ferry Historical Society; New York State Society of Sons of the American Revolution; Baptist Church; personal aid; personal loan; Philadelphia National Bank; New York Central & Hudson River Railroad Company; magazine publishing proposal; job applicants; paint business; Yale University; University of Chicago; Western Reserve Historical Society; Blue Ribbon Temperance Meetings; Baptist Young People's Union; Women's Educational Industrial Union; Townsend Library; history of Civil War.
    - Tracy - Tuttle, Julia D., 204.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 0001, Box 47, Folder 350)
      Baptist Church; passbook; Drum & Fife Corps; interview request; sheriff's jury; Standard Oil Company employee; payment of real estate taxes; property management; Vassar College; trotting horses; New York Central and Hudson River Railroad Company; real estate; Episcopal Church; insurance; Colored Baptist Church; stock market activity; Northern Pacific Railroad Company; University of Rochester; personal matters; character reference; Baptist University in Nebraska; Methodist Episcopal Church; personal loan; personal aid; books for sale; health of John D. Rockefeller; Adirondack Sanitarium; Cleveland Homeopathic Hospital College; Society for Instruction in First Aid to the Injured; Sweden missionary; job applicant; India missionary; Charity Organization Society; New York "World" newspaper; Foreign Mission Board of the Southern Baptist Convention; Shaw University; Industrial Education Association; New York Post-Graduate Hospital; Ohio State University; business loan; Commonwealth Iron Company; Little Mountain Club; Women's Repository (cooperative).
    - Tuttle, Martha M., 1884-July 17, 1893; 148.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 0205, Box 47, Folder 351)
      John D. Rockefeller office telegrapher; Standard Oil Trust shares; office procedures; personnel matters; Forest Hill.
    - Tuttle, Martha M. - Tysse, 95.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 0353, Box 47, Folder 352)
      John D. Rockefeller office telegrapher; Standard Oil Trust shares; office procedures; personnel matters; Forest Hill; India missionary; courier in England; horse for sale; Northern Pacific Railroad Company completion ceremony; Johns Hopkins University; real estate business proposal.
    - U, 140.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 0448, Box 47, Folder 353)
      Painting for sale; German Baptist Church Sunday school; real estate; Rody Patterson Fund; Union League Club; University and School Extension; Brooklyn Teachers' Association; Grande Ligne Mission, Canada; Cleveland Baptist Union; insurance business; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church Sunday school and mission work; personal loan; personal aid; Boy's Brigade; Ireland missionary; Baptist Church.
    - Vail - Valentine, 107.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 0588, Box 47, Folder 354)
      New York Exchange for Woman's Work; Standard Oil Company auditor; accountancy; John D. Rockefeller real estate in Cleveland; insurance; stock market activity; Standard Oil Trust shares; horses; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church Sunday school and mission work; personal aid.
    - Van Aken - Vaughan, G., 128.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 0695, Box 47, Folder 355)
      Baptist Church; Pitcairn Island missionary; American Baptist Publication Society; Baptist Church Sunday school; job applicant; personal aid; John D. Rockefeller cousins; family matters; personal loan; trotting horses; child labor and women in the workplace; business loan; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); Oberlin College; New York Port Society; Baptist youth education questionnaire; Sanitary Aid Society; Grand Army of the Republic Mission; Vassar College; real estate; Washington Hospital for Foundlings; personal matters; China missionary; oriental air importers; Vassar College board of trustees; F. T. Gates report.
    - Vaughan, R. - Vyse, 118.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 0823, Box 48, Folder 356)
      Adirondack Park Association; personal aid; horses; Baptist Review Association; "Baptist Quarterly Review;" Standard Oil Company employee; F. T. Gates report; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); reception for descendants of Christopher Columbus; Chamber of Commerce; New York Historical Society; American Geographical Society; real estate; New York Steam Company; Charity Organization Society; personal matters; Standard Oil Company executive compensation; College for the Training of Teachers; Baptist Church; University of Chicago; temperance laws; National Republican Convention; "The Voice" (temperance publication); business loan; Maternity Hospital; German Baptist Mission.
    - S. C. W. - Waller, E. S., 120.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 0941, Box 48, Folder 357)
      Newspaper attack on John D. Rockefeller; urges charity; personal aid; oil newspaper; University of Michigan; Baptist Church; Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); German Union Evangelical Protestant Church; business proposal; investment advice; Wagner Palace Car Company; John D. Rockefeller travel arrangements; Bible Institute for Home and Foreign Missions (Dwight L. Moody); Chicago Evangelization Society; American Institute of Civics; Cleveland University of Medicine and Surgery; Wake Forest College; etchings for sale; temperance work; France missionary; McAll Mission; Thanksgiving Dinner Charity; Colored Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); fund for Julia Dent Grant (widow of U. S. Grant); Grand Army of the Republic; paintings for sale; Southwestern Baptist University; job applicant; Mariners' Temple; children's aid; business loan.
    - Waller, Edgar E. - Warden, 133.0 pages (Reel 40, Frame 1061, Box 48, Folder 358)
      Unfermented wine; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; Josephine Mission; driftwood barrels for sale; business loan; plumber; Baptist Church; Law and Order League; piano for sale; Women's Baptist Home Mission Society Training School; United Society of Christian Endeavor; public library; Women's Home; Yankton College; F. T. Gates report; personal aid; carriages; Standard Oil Trust executive; personal matters; Standard Oil Trust shares; underground cable investment.
    - Wardle - Washington, B. T., 145.0 pages (Box 48, Folder 359, Reel 41, Frame 0001)
      Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA); American Temperance Union; Baptist Church; Standard Oil Company executive; building services; holiday schedules; office supplies; personnel matters; Cleveland Homeopathic Hospital College; Reform Club; silver standard; fertilizer for sale; Ireland missionary; telescope viewing; Euclid Avenue Baptist Church; trotting horses; personal aid; Episcopal Church; Tuskegee Normal School for Training Colored Teachers.
    - Washington, Lucy H., 103.0 pages (Box 48, Folder 360, Reel 41, Frame 0146)
      Temperance worker; John D. Rockefeller contributions; personal aid; student assistance; Wellesley College; Vassar College; Women's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU); Baptist Church.
    - Washington, S. - Waterbury, M. A., 92.0 pages (Box 48, Folder 361, Reel 41, Frame 0249)
      Baptist Church; Washington Street Memorial Arch; Episcopal Church; personal aid.
    - Waterhouse & Chesebrough - Webster, S. B., 194.0 pages (Box 48, Folder 362, Reel 41, Frame 0341)